

Christian Lawson

Richmond VA, 23224

cllawson02@gmail.com +1 630 430 5591 Project portfolio:

https://axzxc99.github.io/Web-Portfolio-Christian-Lawson/

'See a Need, Fill a Need.'~ Bigweld, Robots (2005). I am a software developer and tech enthusiast with extensive experience in the field. I've been employed ever since I was 17 and my background in coding, problem-solving, and project management allow me to transform ideas into practical solutions. I am motivated by the potential of technology to drive positive change and innovation. Alongside my technical expertise, I am committed to promoting diversity and inclusion in the tech industry. Let's connect and work together to shape the future through technology.

Driver's Licensed

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer.

Work Experience

Computer Operator III

IGT - Richmond, VA

August 2022 to Present

Troubleshooting & overseeing major Virginia casino machine operations.

Electrical Assembler

Video Aerial Systems - Madison Heights, VA October 2020 to August 2022

Assembled antennas used for various applications including but not limited to drones, video equipment, and Wi-Fi adapters.

Website Consultant

Independent Contractor for Atelier 11 - Lynchburg, VA July 2020 to August 2022

In addition to full-time work, I found and corrected web problems with Atelier 11, Ltd.'s website to support their marketing efforts.

Line Cook

Wasabi Japanese Steakhouse & Sushi Bar -Lynchburg, VA

December 2019 to August 2020

I cooked/prepped the food and cleaned the restaurant.

Store Associate

Walmart Inc - Lynchburg, VA October 2018 to December 2019 Unloaded freight truck daily. Stocked freight. Maintained store.

Crew Member

Wendy's Inc - Lynchburg, VA November 2017 to May 2018

Cooked, cleaned, took orders, general maintenance of the restaurant while maintaining honor roll.

Education

Associates

Central Virginia Community College - Lynchburg, VA September 2018 to Present

Advanced Diploma

E C Glass High School - Lynchburg, VA September 2014 to June 2018

Skills

- C++ (2 years)
- CSS (5 years)
- Html (5 years)
- Java (3 years)
- Lua (3 years)

- PHP (5 years)
- Sales (1 year)
- Retail (1 year)
- Customer Service (3 years)
- Excel (1 year)

- Microsoft Office (1 year)
- Microsoft Word (1 year)
- Inventory (1 year)
- Cash Handling (1 year)

- JavaScript (5 years)
- Linux (5 years)
- Web Design (3 years)

- HTML5 (5 years)
- XML (2 years)
- User Interface (UI) (2 years)

Git (2 years)

- GitHub (2 years)
- Node.js (4 years)

Certifications and Licenses

CompTIA ITF+

April 2020 to Present

Introduction to Cloud Computing

January 2022 to Present

"This course provides a foundational understanding of cloud computing, covering its key concepts, historical context, business relevance, leading service providers like AWS, Google, IBM, Microsoft, and industry case studies." A course authorized by IBM.

Introduction to Web Development with HTML, CSS, JavaScript

March 2022 to Present

"This course starts with an explanation of internet servers and clients, then delves into Cloud application development, covering front-end and back-end development. It emphasizes essential languages like HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for front-end development." A course authorized by IBM.

Developing Cloud Native Applications

April 2022 to Present

"Learn to develop cloud-native applications from inception to implementation. This course covers crucial cloud concepts, specific development tools and techniques, the Cloud Native Computing Foundation, hybrid cloud's influence on app developers, and focuses on modernization and continuous integration/delivery."

Material Covered:

- Describe Cloud Native and DevOps concepts and methodologies.
- Build and deploy code to IBM Cloud using DevOps

tools and services.

- Create a Node.js application on IBM Cloud
- Use REST APIs in your app to store and retrieve data in a "NoSQLCloudantDatabas".

Getting Started with Git and GitHub

May 2022 to Present

"Explore collaborative version control and Git platforms in this course, emphasizing key Git concepts like branching, repositories, and commands. Learn practical skills such as forking, cloning, and merging workflows, as well as using GitHub for teamwork and common Git operations. Developed by experienced IBM practitioners, the course offers hands-on experience, including labs and a final project to build your portfolio through a public/open-source GitHub project."

Developing Cloud Apps with Node.js and React

May 2022 to Present

"This course focuses on server-side JavaScript and frameworks, aiming to streamline web and embedded systems development. Node.js and React's significance in cloud application development is underscored by Stack Overflow's 2020 survey, where Node.js leads in usage (51.4%) and is highly favored (66.8%) in 'Other Frameworks, Libraries, and Tools.' React is the second most-used (35.9%) and also popular (66.9%) in the 'Web Frameworks' category. Designed to foster success in this thriving cloud computing sector, the course caters to IT professionals, recent graduates, decision-makers, and individuals from diverse fields looking to gain valuable cloud computing knowledge." A course authorized by IBM.

<u>Assessments</u>

Basic Computer Skills: PC — Highly Proficient

May 2019

Measures a candidate's ability to perform basic computer operations, navigate a Windows OS, and troubleshoot common computer problems.

Full results: Highly Proficient

Problem Solving — Familiar

May 2019

Analyzing relevant information when solving problems. Full results: Familiar

Outside Sales - Highly Proficient

December 2019

Actively listening and responding

appropriately; performing common sales calculations. Full results: <u>Highly</u> Proficient

Customer Focus & Orientation — Proficient

August 2019

Responding to customer situations with sensitivity. Full results: Proficient

Attention to Detail — Highly Proficient

July 2019

Identifying differences in materials, following instructions, and detecting details among distracting information.

Full results: Highly Proficient

Mechanical Skills: Aptitude — Expert

July 2019

Measures a candidate's ability to understand and apply mechanical concepts and processes. Full results:

Expert

Data Entry — Expert

May 2019

Measures a candidate's ability to accurately input data and effectively manage databases. Full results: Expert

Technical Support — Proficient

January 2020

Performing software, hardware, and network operations. Full results: Proficient

Cashier Skills - Expert

June 2020

Counting cash, processing transactions, following written procedures, and attending to details. Full results: Expert

Basic Computer Skills: PC — Highly Proficient

August 2020

Performing basic computer operations, navigating a Windows OS, and troubleshooting common computer problems.

Full results: Highly Proficient

Technical Support — Proficient

August 2020

Performing software, hardware, and network operations. Full results: Proficient

Sales Skills — Highly Proficient

September 2020

Influencing and negotiating with customers Full results: Highly Proficient

Programming Fundamentals — Highly Proficient

August 2020

Designed by engineering managers and real-world employers, this test gives you hard data points to evaluate technical competency.

Full results: Highly Proficient